<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Steel City Ruby Conf]]></title>
  <link href="http://scrc-octopress.heroku.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scrc-octopress.heroku.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T07:21:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://scrc-octopress.heroku.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Shouldn't Code Alone]]></title>
    <link href="http://scrc-octopress.heroku.com/blog/2012/05/04/why-you-shouldnt-code-alone/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T08:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://scrc-octopress.heroku.com/blog/2012/05/04/why-you-shouldnt-code-alone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I work for a decent sized manufacturing company in the Pittsburgh area. I am the
only ruby developer. We have another developer on staff, but our
responsibilities don&#8217;t usually overlap and he doesn&#8217;t know ruby. After joining
this company, I was eventually tasked with writing web apps. Now, my background
is Computer Engineering and I spent a considerable time learning lower level
programming, C/C++ and even Assembly. I thought it would be fun to learn, so I
got some books and got to work.</p>

<p>Why was this bad? It really wasn&#8217;t. Learning a new language and framework was a
lot of fun. BUT BUT BUT; it was painful at times. I had no resources besides
books, Google, and online mailing lists to find answers. Granted they were very
helpful, but I had no idea what I was missing. I would spend hours trying to
figure out some obscure bug in my code, or waiting for an answer on Stack
Overflow. I was getting ever more frustrated, especially with the speed that
Rails was moving at the time. I felt like a huge failure. How dumb could I be?
All of these cool people were making awesome stuff with Rails. What&#8217;s my
problem?!!!</p>

<p>Then I heard about these Ruby Brigades that were forming. Lo and behold,
Pittsburgh was forming one. I almost didn&#8217;t go. I was afraid. I knew I would not
know a single person there. I was obviously incapable of learning. For some
reason, I decided to go. Guess what, I didn&#8217;t know anyone there. Slowly I
started to meet people and talk about what I was doing. I&#8217;ll stress that this
took time, several meetings. As I slowly got over my anxiety, I started to make
friends and share my problems with Ruby. They challenged me to get better, and
they helped me when I got stuck. It was awesome.</p>

<p>Ever since, I have continued to have great experiences and new opportunities.
After hearing two people talking about <a href="http://mendicantuniversity.org/">Mendicant University</a>, I applied. I actually wasn&#8217;t
accepted the first time. This should have been devastating for me, but once
again my new friends came to the rescue. Steve Klabnik messaged me and told me I
had just missed the cutoff, that it came down to several of us and only a few
open spots. He encouraged me to apply again. I did, and I completed the core
skills course. Yay! I&#8217;ve got involved with planning this conference. I&#8217;ve even
sent a few pull requests to open source projects, like <a href="http://hackety.com/">Hackety Hack</a>. It&#8217;s hard to describe how much this has changed me,
submitting to open source is something I never really thought I could do. I
still screw up and feel stupid, but I know that I&#8217;m not the only one.</p>

<p>Don&#8217;t code alone. Get involved. Meet new people. Just coding for a day job is
fine, but there is a whole other world out there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Steel City Ruby Conf Came to Be]]></title>
    <link href="http://scrc-octopress.heroku.com/blog/2012/05/03/how-steel-city-ruby-conf-came-to-be/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T22:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://scrc-octopress.heroku.com/blog/2012/05/03/how-steel-city-ruby-conf-came-to-be</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once upon a time, in an IRC room not so far away, a few people from the
Pittsburgh Ruby Users Group were talking about the awesome time we had just had
at Ruby Conf 2011. We were really excited and had lots of neat ideas, including
this one:</p>

<pre> carols10cents: we should have a conference in pittsburgh! </pre>


<p>There was much agreement, and thus the brainstorming began! We have a google doc
with all sorts of ideas. Some of those are being used this year, some were a bit
too ambitious for our first year ;) We also called it &#8220;Project Octoconf&#8221; for a
while so that we didn&#8217;t get stuck on picking a name&#8211; not because we have any
affiliation with Github/octocat, but because we see Pittsburgh Ruby, and
Pittsburgh in general, reaching into lots of different things and slowly taking
over the world, quietly and for good, of course :D</p>

<p>Since there are so many Ruby conferences though, what would make someone want to
come to ours? Well, what <em>about</em> all those Ruby conferences? Where do you start?
What if you&#8217;re not sure about this whole conference scene? What all goes on
there? Won&#8217;t it be all people who have been going to conferences forever?</p>

<p>So we decided to try to be the best Ruby conference for someone&#8217;s first Ruby
conference. We feel strongly that interacting with the community at conferences
is one of the great things about programming in Ruby, and we&#8217;d like to help
people get into that.</p>

<p>To that end, we&#8217;re trying to keep costs down (and Pittsburgh helps with that as
it&#8217;s a relatively cheap city), do outreach to people who haven&#8217;t been to
conferences before, and plan activities with a new conference goer in mind.</p>

<p>We are so grateful and excited for all the progress we&#8217;ve made and all the
people who have helped us so far, and we hope you&#8217;ll join us for the culmination
of these efforts in August!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
